Waterbury (CT) Area Immigrant Oral History Collection 2009.0014
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Waterbury (CT) Area Immigrant Oral History Collection, Univeristy of Connecticut Urban and Community Studies Program.
2003-2011.
2009.0014
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.3 Linear feet
The collection consists of transcripts of interviews conducted by students enrolled in Professor Ruth Glasser's history classes as part of the Urban and Community Studies Program on the Waterbury campus of the University of Connecticut. The collection is primarily interviews of immigrants living in Waterbury and nearby towns although some other towns in other parts of Connecticut are also represented. Most of the collection consists of interviews with more recent [post 1965] immigrants but there are a few with immigrants or children of immigrants who came in an earlier era.
60 PDF files.
Various.
History
The collection has emerged from two history classes taught at the Waterbury Campus of the University of Connecticut, History of Latinos in the United States and Immigrants and the Shaping of American History. Additional interviews were independent projects conducted by students and the instructor, Ruth Glasser. Interviews in the collection date from 2002 and additions are added on a regular basis.
Scope and Content
The collection contains primarily oral history interviews of immigrants living in Waterbury and nearby towns. A small number document the immigrant experience in other parts of Connecticut. Most of the collection consists of interviews with more recent [post 1965] immigrants but there are a few with immigrants or children of immigrants who came in an earlier era. There are a few pre-1965 Cold War era immigrant stories. Different Latin America n countries and Puerto Rico are particularly well represented, there are more interviews of people from Albania or from ethnic Albanians from Macedonia than anywhere else in Europe although there are some other European-based immigrants including those from former Yugoslavia n areas such as Bosnia or Croatia, also Portugal, Scotland, Germany, England, France, Russia. Other interviewees are from Asia and various islands of the English-speaking Caribbean. There are a couple of Cape Verdean interviews and one Egyptian interview. The transcripts are available as searchable PDF (portable document format) documents and require Adobe Acrobat Reader (7 or higher) to view.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by country of origin.
Series I: Interviews ( 2003-2011 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut's ethnic communities. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk. Similar oral histories can be found in the Center for Oral History Interviews--Peoples of Connecticut Project, the finding aid of which is available here.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Custodial History
The oral histories were conducted and transcripts produced by students enrolled in courses taught at the Waterbury campus of the University of Connecticut. The transcripts were collected by the instructor, Ruth Glasser.
Alternative Form Available
Paper copies of the transcripts are also available in the Dodd Research Center. Inquire at the reference desk for more information.
Acquisition Information
The transcripts were transferred by Dr. Ruth Glasser beginning in 2008.
Oral Histories.; Waterbury (Conn.)
- Series I: Interviews, 2003-2011 (Box 1)
  - Albania
    - Kambo, Andi, 2011
    - Llulla, Ada and Llulla, Eda, 2003
    - 2008
    - Rashiti, Miradije, 2008
    - Spaho, Eredia, 2008
  - Brazil
    - DeCastro, Bernardo, 2008
  - Canada
    - Perreault, John, 2011
    - Perreault, Justin, 2011
  - Colombia
    - Medina, Mariela, 2004
    - Zvonarek, Karlo, 2004
    - Roseman, Shelley, 2009
  - Costa Rica
    - Aguirre, Yesenia, 2004
  - Dominican Republic
    - Garcia, Adelaida, 2003
    - Hernandez, Francisco, 2003
    - Olivo, Tomas, 2011
    - Perez, Oscar, 2008
    - Batista, Rosario, 2009
    - Benitez, Marlen, 2009
    - Mazueta, Elizabeth, 2009
    - Olivo, Tomas, 2009
    - Rodriguez, Thomas, 2009
  - Ecuador
    - Rivera, Natalia, 2008
    - Quintana, Pedro, 2009
  - France
    - Miserez, Claude, 2008
  - Greece
    - Galanos, Arthur, 2011
  - Guatemala
    - Solis, Arthur, 2003
    - Flores, Roberto, 2009
    - Sarmiento, Angelica, 2009
    - Sarmiento, Gyancarlo, 2009
  - Honduras
    - Petrisky, Digna, 2011
  - Hungary
    - Nemeth, Lazlo, 2008
  - Italy
    - Fazio, Angelo, 2011
    - Guerrera, Frank, 2011
    - Ralph, 2011
  - Jamaica
    - Sinclair, Yolanda, 2011
  - Kosovo
    - Mustafa, Drilon, 2011
  - Mexico
    - Paris and Haydee, 2004
    - Hernandez, Pablo, 2008
    - Benitez, Jimmy, 2009
  - Nicaragua
    - Vilma, 2006
    - Briceno, Flor, 2009
  - Poland
    - Waluk, Anna, 2011
  - Portugal
    - Adaes, Olga, 2011
    - Adaes, Silvia, 2011
    - Costa, Julio, 2003
  - Puerto Rico
    - Caro, Eugenio, 2005
    - Hernandez, Gladys, 2005
    - Soldevila, Clorinda, 2005
    - Soto, Antonio, 2005
    - Andiarena, Enid, 2009
    - Arce, Geraldo and Esther, 2009
    - Benitez, Dariel, 2009
    - Conway, Sandy, 2009
    - Diaz, Keyshla, 2009
    - Figeroa, Lydia, 2009
    - Santiago, Aurora, 2009
    - Santiago, Madeline, 2009
    - Torres, Christopher, 2009
  - Venezuela
    - Ovalles, Ligia, 2011